[{"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c12d", "question": "Live Aid was organized to benefit which starving country?\u00a0", "answer": "Ethiopia", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c064", "question": "In the video game \"God of War\", which mythological character must Kratos defeat at the end to finish the game?", "answer": "Ares (the God of War)", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c39f", "question": "When a human bone breaks only on one side, it is called what?", "answer": "Greenstick fracture", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b456", "question": "What year did Abraham Lincoln deliver the Gettysburg Address?", "answer": "1863", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5e72ce4cd0874f1a5e2d1c27", "question": "Which prominent US statesman was known as \"The Great Compromiser\" and helped allegedly swing the 1824 election?", "answer": "Henry Clay", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c99f", "question": "What phenomenon is caused by the gravitational attraction of the Earth's moon?", "answer": "Tides", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133aec7", "question": "Which British Sailor and Explorer was killed by Hawaiian natives in 1779?", "answer": "James Cook", "category": "history"}, {"id": "590088eccf842fa4c4ba968b", "question": "In which Shakespeare play would you find Constable Elbow?", "answer": "Measure for Measure", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe909b101dd7bf43be5e890", "question": "What is the outside covering of a plant's root called?", "answer": "Root epidermis", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c2fb", "question": "What vitamin complex includes thiamine, niacin and riboflavin?", "answer": "Vitamin B", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a3ae", "question": "Which city is the capital of Australia?", "answer": "Canberra", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133aeb8", "question": "Who was CIA Director from 1976 to 1977?", "answer": "George H.W. Bush", "category": "history"}, {"id": "590723043745b36be7303a04", "question": "Who directed the 2003 film \"Love Actually\"?", "answer": "Richard Curtis", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339176", "question": "Which Seinfeld creator plays himself in the TV show \"Curb Your Enthusiasm\"?", "answer": "Larry David", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fdfb82b003d27d341092bbb", "question": "Where is the world's oldest royal residence still in use?", "answer": "England", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338bba", "question": "Who went down to Hades to rescue his wife Eurydice?", "answer": "Orpheus", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a252", "question": "What 1980s TV show starred Bruce Willis in a detective agency?", "answer": "Moonlighting", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd40", "question": "Who has been the pole sitter at a record six Indy 500s, from 1979 to 1991?", "answer": "Rick Mears", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b538", "question": "How many players are there on a soccer team?", "answer": "Eleven", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5c90d22852800b05cac20f13", "question": "What are the names of the 5 Space Shuttle Orbiters used by NASA on manned spaceflight missions?", "answer": "Columbia, Challenger, Discovery, Atlantis, Endeavour", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe7ce72877e98cb97778a42", "question": "Which place is dubbed as \"The Salad Bowl of the Philippines\"?", "answer": "Benguet", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133cad5", "question": "How many zeroes are in the number one trillion?", "answer": "12", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fec8d52ec223966ae8f8851", "question": "Which actor voices Miles Morales in \"Into the Spider-Verse\"?", "answer": "Shameik Moore", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ffa38c9c73aa70ea0b70ad5", "question": "Basundi is a dairy product that is popular in which part of the world?", "answer": "India", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c686", "question": "What is the only bird that can fly backwards?", "answer": "The hummingbird", "category": "science"}, {"id": "601b4a7649076251badbeab6", "question": "Who patented the concept of a flat engine in 1896?", "answer": "Karl Benz", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b412", "question": "In what year was nylon first synthesized?", "answer": "1935", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b72b", "question": "How do Japanese children refer to Santa Claus?", "answer": "Santa no ojisan or Uncle Santa", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a0a0", "question": "Happy Days was a spin off from what US TV show?", "answer": "Love American Style", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a41e", "question": "What is the modern day equivalent of Formosa?", "answer": "Taiwan", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe4b68406d333868d34d6f2", "question": "Which British royal family changed its name from Saxe-Coburg-Gotha in 1917?", "answer": "Windsors", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ff66b1e52a821ff76ae8b0c", "question": "People who scavenged the sewers of London during the Victoria era were called what?", "answer": "Tosher", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59067b9aff9c0647b50a8066", "question": "What smartglasses were you able to purchase on November 10 2016, from a proprietary vending machine?", "answer": "Spectacles", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a05", "question": "What was the first movie adaptation of a Hannibal Lecter novel to feature Anthony Hopkins?", "answer": "The Silence of the Lambs", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bcf0", "question": "Who's responsible for \"The Ballad of The Sad Cafe\"?", "answer": "Carson McCullers", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe7c99e877e98cb977789f8", "question": "On the first of November, Spain celebrates \"Todos los Santos\" which translates to what in English?", "answer": "All Saints Day", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339182", "question": "Who was the actor who played Charles in the movie \"Four Weddings and a Funeral\"?", "answer": "Hugh Grant", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ff6669452a821ff76ae8af9", "question": "What Jewish custom was adopted by Southern Americans for the New Year?", "answer": "Eating black-eyed peas", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b00", "question": "What 1960's television series was set at the fictitious Coral Key Park & Marine Preserve?", "answer": "Flipper", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c1ff", "question": "Which country were the 1988 Winter Olympic Games held in?", "answer": "Canada", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d68", "question": "Who played the role of TV's B. L. Stryker?", "answer": "Burt Reynolds", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a167", "question": "Who played Sarah Conner in the 1991 film \"Terminator 2: Judgment Day\"?", "answer": "Linda Hamilton", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b6d4", "question": "Where is the stop positioned on traditional roller skates?", "answer": "The toe", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b24c", "question": "Whom did the Daughters of the American Revolution bar from singing at Constitution Hall in 1936?", "answer": "Marian Anderson", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fecc122ec223966ae8f8865", "question": "The 1982 football game that birthed \"The Play\", was between which schools?", "answer": "Stanford and Berkeley", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338dd5", "question": "From what language did English borrow the word \"canyon\"?", "answer": "Spanish", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe93d2c6bd93ce3a4e5f6b0", "question": "The conversion of ethanol to ethanoic acid is an example of what?", "answer": "Oxidation", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fefa3a36ce05a3942286ea6", "question": "Which director took out ads asking people not to ruin a film's twist ending?", "answer": "Alfred Hitchcock", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fdc15c4469bb8041d07a08c", "question": "What does \"dim sum\" mean in English?", "answer": "Touching heart", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339fb8", "question": "What video made stars of the overall-clad \"Sal\" and \"Harv\"?", "answer": "Money for Nothing", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ff66c8852a821ff76ae8b12", "question": "Which Christian holiday is directly related to the observance of the March equinox?", "answer": "Easter is traditionally celebrated on the Sunday after the first full moon that occurs on or after the March equinox.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c471", "question": "What computer programming language is often referred to by coders as \"Camel\"?", "answer": "Perl", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113396de", "question": "Which pop group was initially named \"The Pendletones\"?", "answer": "The Beach Boys", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f64", "question": "Whose halftime set at Super Bowl XLI was performed during a downpour?", "answer": "Prince's", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a8af", "question": "In what city would you find Centennial Olympic Park?", "answer": "Atlanta", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b1f4", "question": "The Arc de Triomphe was originally built to commemorate France's triumph in what 1805 battle?", "answer": "Austerlitz", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac43", "question": "During World War I how did the Germany Army make ammonia for explosives?", "answer": "Using the Haber Process", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5cb70bb8f96e155acab35d26", "question": "What is the longest running Star Trek series of all time in terms of total episodes?", "answer": "Star Trek: The Next Generation", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113393c6", "question": "What Hollywood director had a small role in the movie \"The Blues Brothers\"?", "answer": "Steven Spielberg", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b02b", "question": "How old was Evel Knievel when he died?", "answer": "69", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fd6a2da6c0f9723ab15cb47", "question": "Who was the first president to receive full-time Secret Service protection?", "answer": "Theodore Roosevelt", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59e80464de59ea584496fea4", "question": "What are the names of the two adult Dalmatians in the novel \"The Hundred and One Dalmatians\"?", "answer": "Pongo and Missis", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bec9", "question": "\"Dig 'em Frog\" was the mascot for which Kellogg's breakfast cereal?", "answer": "Honey Smacks", "category": "general"}, {"id": "600242bc4be4723ccac2218b", "question": "Which French novelist wrote the seven-volume novel \"In Search of Lost Time\" (often translated as \"Remembrance of Times Past\")?", "answer": "Marcel Proust", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339205", "question": "In what movie does Eddie Murphy swap identities with Dan Aykroyd?", "answer": "Trading Places", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a579", "question": "What is the capital of the state of Texas?", "answer": "Austin", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ff511daff04d658268c92cb", "question": "What Greek general is responsible for the project that generated most of the surviving structures on the Acropolis?", "answer": "Pericles\u00a0promoted the arts and literature, which made Athens the educational and cultural center of the ancient Greek world.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bfef", "question": "What type of creature is located on top of the Calcutta Cup?", "answer": "Elephant", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59a1a2d112f2a7826b9b8720", "question": "In what 1988 did film David Bowie play Pontius Pilate?", "answer": "Last Temptation of Christ", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5963702f967692ea851899b8", "question": "What singer scored a #1 hit in 1999 with a duet with his wife, Lisa Hartman entitled, \"When I Said I Do\"?", "answer": "Clint Black", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339cf4", "question": "Where did the Gilmore Girls reside?", "answer": "Stars Hollow", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "601601cffe83fe1f2a824c62", "question": "What does the star on the top of a Christmas tree symbolize?", "answer": "This is symbolic of the \"Star of Bethlehem\", the same star the Magi are said to have seen.", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f031133887e", "question": "Which character do the events of the narrative's plot revolve around and with whom the audience identifies itself with?", "answer": "The Protagonist", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "58f16690f7c52aae91cc07af", "question": "What is New Year's Eve called in Scotland?", "answer": "Hogmanay", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e1f", "question": "What artist sold only one painting, \"The Red Vineyard\", during his lifetime?", "answer": "Vincent van Gogh", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a01", "question": "When is Cinderella required to leave the ball?", "answer": "By midnight", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "592eaee8f83302ff91e4648e", "question": "What does the Latin phrase \"ad hoc\" literally mean?", "answer": "For this", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe12e01e39efa6330e0fed1", "question": "Where is the most expensive hotel suite in the U.S.?", "answer": "Las Vegas", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339647", "question": "In which film did Michael Douglas play the part of Gordon Gekko?", "answer": "Wall Street", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5a25ef236682715b82711cd4", "question": "What year did the Invasion of Normandy take place?", "answer": "1944", "category": "history"}, {"id": "58bb357de368446ca7bd6853", "question": "What year was the AeroPress invented?", "answer": "2005", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a389", "question": "What country is Ibiza a part of?", "answer": "Spain", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a9dc", "question": "On which island will you find \"Adams Peak\"?", "answer": "Sri Lanka", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339cc1", "question": "What band's Greatest Hits album set a US record by going 29 times platinum?", "answer": "Eagles'", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bfd3", "question": "What is the NATO phonetic alphabet word for \"J\"?", "answer": "Juliett", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fb08a91cf631c2414a13b61", "question": "What Nashville venue was Taylor Swift playing at when she was discovered?", "answer": "The Bluebird Cafe", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c01", "question": "What is actor Jack Nicholson's birthdate?", "answer": "April 22, 1937", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ff5139aff04d658268c92dd", "question": "The last execution in the Tower of London took place during what war?", "answer": "World War II\u00a0-- Josef Jakobs, a German soldier, was executed by firing squad on August 14, 1941 for espionage.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113399eb", "question": "How many of the seven dwarfs had mustaches?", "answer": "None", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca0d", "question": "Which island is the Dodo originally from?", "answer": "Mauritus", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338fc5", "question": "Which detective story writer created the character Tuppence Beresford?", "answer": "Agatha Christie", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be93", "question": "What company opened its first Italian eatery at Brooklyn's Kings Plaza Shopping Center in 1967?", "answer": "Sbarro", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c9a4", "question": "With what body part is otology involved?", "answer": "The ears", "category": "science"}, {"id": "601371c0138175489539638d", "question": "Which musician wrote the theme song for Johnny Carson's \"The Tonight Show\"?", "answer": "Paul Anka -- The song earned him massive royalties. According to Anka, he received $200 every time the song was played.", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca1c", "question": "What type of animal is a Borzoi?", "answer": "A dog", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c020", "question": "Who is the inventor of the cash register?", "answer": "James Ritty", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c02c", "question": "What does Amoco stand for?", "answer": "American Oil Company", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6017372e44491cbd7c5a1785", "question": "During the American Civil War, what ship engaged the iron-clad ship USS Monitor off Hampton Roads, Virginia?", "answer": "On March 9, 1862, the USS Monitor engaged the CSS Virginia in a naval battle that resulted in a draw.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe3e86c38e4e5d4832e630a", "question": "In the Bible, whose vineyard did King Ahab wish to acquire?", "answer": "Naboth's", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f42", "question": "Who created the character of Yogi Bear?", "answer": "William Hanna and Joseph Barbera", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59071d7b3745b36be73039d8", "question": "What year did the Space Race between the United States and the Soviet Union start?", "answer": "1955", "category": "history"}, {"id": "600f7070a9e54d890926f6d6", "question": "Which river carved the Grand Canyon?", "answer": "Colorado River -- Five to six million years ago, the river carved through sediment and volcanic rock to form the Grand Canyon.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339dff", "question": "Whose tombstone bears the inscription \"That's All Folks\"?", "answer": "Mel Blanc", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a9b9", "question": "What country is the \"pearl of the orient seas\"?", "answer": "Philippines", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a08c", "question": "What band released the hit song \"Radio Gaga\"?", "answer": "Queen", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a617", "question": "What country's major seaport is Alexandria?", "answer": "Egypt", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c792", "question": "Cheetahs are native to what two continents?", "answer": "Africa and Asia", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c92c", "question": "The comma bacillus causes what disease?", "answer": "Cholera", "category": "science"}, {"id": "58d11a2a4fea7fe947a22294", "question": "\"The Diary of a Young Girl\" is also known under what title?", "answer": "The Diary of Anne Frank", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a18c", "question": "Who was the first woman to win an Oscar Best Actress in 1929?", "answer": "Janet Gaynor", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338cfc", "question": "Who wrote \"Memoirs of a Geisha\"?", "answer": "Arthur Golden", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b2c6", "question": "What US state was named for the future James II of England?", "answer": "New York", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd2c", "question": "In what sport are the Beaters in charge of batting away the Bludgers?", "answer": "Quidditch", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fea4973ff048f679a45abb8", "question": "What part of the scientific method tests a hypothesis?", "answer": "Experiment", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe7343eeec85e375820b231", "question": "Who was the first US president to live in the white house?", "answer": "John Adams", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b32", "question": "Who is the one-eyed giant of Greek mythology?", "answer": "Cyclops", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c008", "question": "In 1946, Yvon Petra was the last Wimbledon champion to do what?", "answer": "Wear trousers", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bbb8", "question": "Which tennis star's father represented Iran at boxing in two Olympic Games?", "answer": "Andre Agassi", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338cce", "question": "Stephen Crane's \"The Red Badge of Courage\" is set during which war?", "answer": "US Civil War", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ade3", "question": "What was Liu Bang, founder of the Han Dynasty, posthumously known as?", "answer": "Emperor Gaozu of Han", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fea3f7eff048f679a45ab5f", "question": "Which animal product does an ovo-vegetarian eat?", "answer": "Eggs", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b59b", "question": "What do you call a group of Geese?", "answer": "Gaggle", "category": "general"}, {"id": "60062c7dc9d816e292245c2c", "question": "What artist sold a balloon dog for $58.4 million?", "answer": "In a 2013 sale,\u00a0Jeff Koons\u00a0sold\u00a0Balloon Dog for $58.4 million, the highest price ever paid for an artwork by a living artist.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c92b", "question": "What is a dromedary?", "answer": "One-humped camel", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5b3589615db0d66a186cb54a", "question": "Which popular artist was born as Robyn Fenty in 1988 in Barbados?", "answer": "Rihanna", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe7cae0877e98cb97778a0d", "question": "You can find Grand Teton National Park in which U.S. state?", "answer": "Wyoming", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f0b", "question": "What author created the character of James Qwilleran?", "answer": "Lilian Jackson Braun", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c71f", "question": "What is the 3-letter term for a young goat?", "answer": "A kid", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c93", "question": "How does Juliet die in Shakespeare's \"Romeo and Juliet\"?", "answer": "She stabs herself", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fd6659fa5bfecdd737e0861", "question": "Who were the first people to use currency?", "answer": "Lydians", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe6aa1620565ad31a57c810", "question": "Who was the President Kennedy's Secretary of Defense?", "answer": "Robert McNamara", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e6d", "question": "Who painted \"Irises\"?", "answer": "Vincent van Gogh", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "6007849bbd51d85e222ab65c", "question": "What was the first fruit that was eaten on the moon?", "answer": "Peach", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b65", "question": "How many of the seven dwarfs have beards?", "answer": "6", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a39d", "question": "What European capital celebrated its 2,000th anniversary in 1951?", "answer": "Paris", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133973b", "question": "What do the letters stand for in the band CCR?", "answer": "Creedence Clearwater Revival", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe7cac2877e98cb97778a0b", "question": "In what country can a man be referred to as \"First Footer\"?", "answer": "Scotland", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5a4a959d61d1b4d384d5d67b", "question": "\"White Room\" was a hit off which Cream album?", "answer": "Wheels of Fire", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59c1ce3f7bd84c0ea43ad435", "question": "On which river does the capital of Canada lie?", "answer": "Ottawa River", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fde4a4fc6c6b019850c9a73", "question": "What did the first vending machine dispense?", "answer": "Holy Water", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe0db34fcbed638185eaa08", "question": "Where is the only tropical botanical garden listed on UNESCO's World Heritage Site list?", "answer": "Singapore", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af6f", "question": "Used to complete the first transcontinental railway, the last spike was made of what material?", "answer": "Gold", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f0d", "question": "Demi Moore appeared pregnant on the cover of which magazine in 1991?", "answer": "Vanity Fair", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe7c654877e98cb977789b7", "question": "The Semper Opera House is located where?", "answer": "Dresden, Germany", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338891", "question": "Which side of a book are the even-numbered pages usually on?", "answer": "The left", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fecc81aec223966ae8f888e", "question": "What is the name of the spider that paralyzes Frodo in the film \"The Lord of the Rings: The Return of the King\"?", "answer": "Shelob", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ff3d0254f032c0db195b497", "question": "What was the Year of the Five Emperors?", "answer": "In 193 AD, there were five claimants for the title of Roman Emperor.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b114", "question": "What Spanish explorer became the first governor of Puerto Rico in 1508?", "answer": "Juan Ponce de Leon", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a0d1", "question": "In which film did Kevin Costner make his directorial debut?", "answer": "Dances with Wolves", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133959c", "question": "Who plays the broken-hearted widower in the 2003 movie \"Love Actually\"?", "answer": "Liam Neeson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a087", "question": "Where are Rocket J. Squirrel and Bullwinkle Moose from?", "answer": "Frostbite Falls", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e10", "question": "What British comedian refers to himself as an \"executive transvestite\"?", "answer": "Eddie Izzard", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b80a", "question": "Poutine consists of gravy and cheese curds on top of what?", "answer": "French fries", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c32a", "question": "What part of the eye gives it color?", "answer": "The Iris", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bcf9", "question": "What was the first nonoriginal color of cereal pieces added to Trix in 1980?", "answer": "Purple", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ff0", "question": "What film coined the term \"cameo appearance\" for a brief star turn in a movie?", "answer": "Around the World in Eighty Days", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6008da63f4f3bc4a292f8615", "question": "What did John Wilkes Booth shout after he shot President Lincoln?", "answer": "\"Sic Semper Tyrannis\", which is Latin for \"Thus always to tyrants\".", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338fcd", "question": "The word \"Cyberspace\" appeared for first time in which William Gibson publication?", "answer": "Burning Chrome", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fefbe606ce05a3942286eee", "question": "Who recorded the song \"Everybody Wants to Rule the World\"?", "answer": "Tears For Fears", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ff3cf1b4f032c0db195b48f", "question": "Who was the first Catholic pope?", "answer": "The Roman Catholic Church sees\u00a0Peter\u00a0as the first pope", "category": "history"}, {"id": "591c37f6815febcc896f9277", "question": "What is the sixth sign of the Zodiac?", "answer": "Virgo", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59cdb67065ff7d326b622a96", "question": "Who had 1960's hits with \"Glad All Over\" and \"Bits and Pieces\"?", "answer": "The Dave Clark Five", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "600cc4616de0eb824d4052f2", "question": "\"Jana Gana Mana\" is the national anthem of which Asian country?", "answer": "India", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b8b0", "question": "Which company manufactured the B-29 Superfortress aircraft?", "answer": "Boeing", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a0ba", "question": "Who in the world of music and born 1984 has the real name\u00a0Victoria Christina Hesketh?", "answer": "Little Boots", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "597cdd31e347d002c297e4ed", "question": "Which river forms a border between France and Germany?", "answer": "The Rhine", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133967a", "question": "In the TV show \"The Simpsons\", who learned medicine at \"The Hollywood Upstairs Medical School\"?", "answer": "Dr. Nick Riviera", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113390e1", "question": "What year was Ben Jonson's \"The Alchemist\" first performed?", "answer": "1610", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59071d5e3745b36be73039d7", "question": "What operation brought over 1,500 German scientists, engineers and technicians following the end of World War II to the US to aid in military research?", "answer": "Operation Paperclip", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133904c", "question": "Who wrote the 1952 novel \"Giant\"?", "answer": "Edna Ferber", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "58dba61f874c93a3298b2156", "question": "What defined as \"the ratio between a circle's circumference and its diameter\"?", "answer": "Pi", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5909cc7fbb53d1af658864e1", "question": "Who created Rudolph the Red-Nosed Reindeer?", "answer": "Robert Lewis May", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113390a1", "question": "What is Demeter the god of?", "answer": "Harvest and agriculture", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aaab", "question": "Ankara is the capital of which country?", "answer": "Turkey", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339aca", "question": "On what TV show did the characters often hang out at the Warsaw Tavern?", "answer": "The Drew Carey Show", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe8f43d01dd7bf43be5e820", "question": "TBD stands for what?", "answer": "To Be Determined", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ff0b685e662d71a53651009", "question": "What French ballet term means \"in front\"?", "answer": "Devant", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fea3af5ff048f679a45ab30", "question": "What are the three-time periods of the dinosaurs?", "answer": "Triassic, Jurassic, and Cretaceous", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a262", "question": "What is the name of the summer camp in the \"Friday the 13th\" movie series?", "answer": "Camp Crystal Lake\u00a0", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be7b", "question": "What slang term for the stomach is the highest-scoring ailment in the game \"Operation\"?", "answer": "The Breadbasket", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6015e859fe83fe1f2a824bdb", "question": "Which English king built castles in the 13th century to help conquer Wales?", "answer": "Edward I", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5cb70de5f96e155acab35d35", "question": "What two boxers fought in the famous match-up dubbed the \"Thrilla in Manila\"?", "answer": "Muhammad Ali and Joe Frazier", "category": "general"}, {"id": "60062a82c9d816e292245c19", "question": "What artist created a 43 ft sculpture of a West Highland White Terrier puppy?", "answer": "Jeff Koons (He was commissioned to create the piece for Arolsen Castle in Germany.)", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5be57f7f5415ba52ed6f0aab", "question": "The town of Pisa lies in which Italian region?", "answer": "Tuscany", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ffcfcae9dc5ec6cd98a831e", "question": "What artist's work was involved in a case before the New York Supreme Court in 2010?", "answer": "Julie Mehretu's\u00a0work was the object of a case which involved legal issues over her work and the right of first refusal contracts.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c41", "question": "By what name is the author Samuel Langhorne Clemens better known?", "answer": "Mark Twain", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b793", "question": "In \"The Twelve Days of Christmas\", what did my true love send to me on the fifth day?", "answer": "Five gold rings", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa6b", "question": "What is the capital of the US state of North Carolina?", "answer": "Raleigh", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5a162cc3f01ec323f8491732", "question": "Arnold Schwarzenegger played Douglas Quaid in which 1990 film?", "answer": "Total Recall", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339798", "question": "Who did Michael Jackson marry in May 1994?", "answer": "Lisa Marie Pressley", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe0e45cfcbed638185eaa27", "question": "In which US city can you find \"Bubblegum Alley\"?", "answer": "San Luis Obispo, California", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ff7c0a42b316f4693fb6798", "question": "What is the name for the process of electing a Pope?", "answer": "Conclave", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a4ff", "question": "What city is the capital of Djibouti?", "answer": "Djibouti City", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a6e3", "question": "Grand Mesa is located in which US state?", "answer": "Colorado", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5e90feced7247dfc0fa00309", "question": "In what year was \"Harry Potter and the Sorcerer's Stone\" published in the US?", "answer": "1998", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c091", "question": "What are scaup?", "answer": "Ducks", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a8bd", "question": "What two characters are sculpted on Hannibal, Missouri's Main Street?", "answer": "Tom Sawyer and Huckleberry Finn", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a35c", "question": "Where is Lake Como?", "answer": "Italy", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ef1", "question": "What 1968 hit was the first song to use the phrase \"heavy metal\"?", "answer": "Born to Be Wild", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59029ed3cad1ec93f27df758", "question": "What is champagne substituted with to turn a \"Black Velvet\" cocktail into a \"Poor Man\u2019s Black Velvet\" cocktail?", "answer": "Cider", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe000661cf6db9ac4808d11", "question": "When was Hong Kong transferred from Britain to China?", "answer": "1997", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338874", "question": "What Emily Bronte novel features Heathcliff?", "answer": "Wuthering Heights", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "6017383744491cbd7c5a1796", "question": "What was the first U.S. state to ban billboards?", "answer": "Hawaii -- Billboards were banned in Hawaii in 1927.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c50c", "question": "What playing card symbolizes death?", "answer": "Ace of spades", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339321", "question": "In the movie \"Hangover\", what name did Alan use to refer to his circle of friends?", "answer": "The wolf pack", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c002", "question": "The cocktail \"Margarita\" contains cointreau, lime and which spirit?", "answer": "Tequila", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b6a9", "question": "What traditional Russian instrument looks like a triangular guitar?", "answer": "The balalaika", "category": "general"}, {"id": "594a64302ebb971c1417fba1", "question": "In which US state would you find the \"Everglades\"?", "answer": "Florida", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a24d", "question": "What year did Huey Lewis and the News record the song \"Jacob's Ladder\"?", "answer": "1986", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aac1", "question": "Into what ocean does the Zambezi River flow?", "answer": "Indian", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d21", "question": "What sport is the focus of the movie \"Days of Thunder\"?", "answer": "Car racing", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b8b7", "question": "How many strings are there on a standard violin?", "answer": "4", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe4b5b606d333868d34d6ec", "question": "Which country was the first European nation to reach Japan?", "answer": "Portugal", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113392e4", "question": "In the movie \"Toy Story\" what is the name of the boy next door who blows up toys?", "answer": "Sid", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339553", "question": "Who played Mork and Mindy's baby?", "answer": "Jonathan Winters", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113393c7", "question": "How old was Sean Connery when he first appeared as James Bond?", "answer": "32", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b685", "question": "What insulates the ice cream to prevent it from melting in the hot dish \"Baked Alaska\"?", "answer": "Meringue", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af80", "question": "Who did Dwight Eisenhower defeat twice in presidential elections during the 1950s?", "answer": "Adlai Stevenson", "category": "history"}, {"id": "6015df7afe83fe1f2a824b79", "question": "What woman followed her husband into battle during the American Revolutionary War and took his post when he was killed?", "answer": "Margaret Cochran Corbin", "category": "history"}, {"id": "60137186138175489539638b", "question": "Who served as butler to the von Trapp family in \"The Sound of Music\"?", "answer": "Franz -- He spent several years as a loyal butler in the service of the Von Trapp family before he betrayed them to the Nazis.", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339232", "question": "Who played the Cook County Assessor's Office Clerk in \"The Blues Brothers\"?", "answer": "Steven Spielberg", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba24", "question": "How many World Professional Snooker championships did Joe Davis win?", "answer": "15", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58ab959c86faa38a764be517", "question": "Before starting to produce cars in the late 1940s, what did SAAB originally manufacture?", "answer": "Aircrafts", "category": "general"}, {"id": "600245024be4723ccac221ab", "question": "In Leonardo da Vinci's Annunciation, who is depicted with the virgin Mary?", "answer": "Gabriel -- The angel is sent by God to tell the virgin Mary that she will miraculously conceive and give birth to a son, Jesus.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f48", "question": "What naval hobbyist produced the landmark book \"All the World's Fighting Ships\" in 1898?", "answer": "Fred T. Jane", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339110", "question": "In which play by Tennessee Williams would you encounter the character \"Big Daddy\"?", "answer": "Cat on a Hot Tin Roof", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c1ba", "question": "Which river is often viewed as Russia's national river?", "answer": "Volga", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5febb0ce7e83c707845b2108", "question": "What insect protects peonies from damaging pests?", "answer": "Ants", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fd2d2172596a59cbdfbd38a", "question": "What special power does the titular character possess in \"Matilda\"?", "answer": "Telekinesis", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338959", "question": "What eye complaint is blamed for the reddish tone of some of Monet's paintings?", "answer": "Cataracts", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "596dfd6b9616e6c6d4eba4f5", "question": "What country was the first to send an object to the Moon?", "answer": "The Soviet Union", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113398f1", "question": "In what movie does Steve Martin play the character of Navin Johnson?", "answer": "The Jerk", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59071dcf3745b36be73039de", "question": "What is the nationality of the first woman in space?", "answer": "Soviet/Russian", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a92f", "question": "Where is the Track and field Hall of Fame located?", "answer": "Indianapolis, Indiana", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5e8a66eb9a45431f553a9cd0", "question": "Who played Tim in the cult U.K. sitcom \"Spaced\"?", "answer": "Simon Pegg", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339653", "question": "In the TV show \"The Simpsons\", what vehicle is described as \"A country-fried truck endorsed by a clown\"?", "answer": "Canyonero", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339344", "question": "Who was the first winner of \"American Idol\"?", "answer": "Kelly Clarkson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa7f", "question": "What is Krung Thep is more commonly known as?", "answer": "Bangkok", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fef5cc56ce05a3942286e26", "question": "Elmore City, Oklahoma was the inspiration for what movie?", "answer": "\"Footloose\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133977b", "question": "Where is the film Predator set?", "answer": "South American jungle", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a9a0", "question": "In what country would you find the active volcano \"Taal\"?", "answer": "The Philippines", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a281", "question": "Who preceded Phil Collins as the lead singer of Genesis?", "answer": "Peter Gabriel", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5f9f4335af848b908361b870", "question": "Which is the largest city in Africa?", "answer": "Cairo", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a71e", "question": "What southern city is located on the shores of Lake Pontchartrain?", "answer": "New Orleans", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe0003b1cf6db9ac4808d0f", "question": "What is the tallest building in South America?", "answer": "Gran Torre Santiago, Santiago, Chile", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ffb67ef5dad637d903c8840", "question": "Kersti Kaljulaid was 46 years old when she became the youngest president ever elected to lead which country?", "answer": "Estonia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133928d", "question": "What title was the movie \"Evil Dead III\" released under?", "answer": "Army of Darkness", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5e94d1b05ea27d7a1303aed5", "question": "In the world of LEGO, what does SNOT mean?", "answer": "Studs Not On Top", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133937d", "question": "In the movie \"Interview with the Vampire\", who cut Lestat's throat?", "answer": "Claudia", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6015f76efe83fe1f2a824c21", "question": "A three-day celebration triduum that involves; Halloween, All Saints Day, and All Souls Day can be referred to as?", "answer": "Allhallowtide, which can also be called Allsaintstide or Hallowtide.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "6016021cfe83fe1f2a824c63", "question": "Which Christian holiday is directly related to the observance of the March equinox?", "answer": "Easter is traditionally celebrated on the Sunday after the first full moon that occurs on or after the March equinox.", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339bad", "question": "Mitch Mitchell and Noel Redding were the two lesser-known members of what rock trio?", "answer": "Jimi Hendrix Experience", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113393f1", "question": "What is the alter ego of the superhero known as the Amazing Spider-Man?", "answer": "Peter Parker", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a36", "question": "On what show did Heather Locklear make her TV debut in a recurring role?", "answer": "Dynasty", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338de7", "question": "From what language did English borrow the word \"kumquat\"?", "answer": "Cantonese", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c006", "question": "What name is given to a year with 366 days?", "answer": "Leap", "category": "general"}]